American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - [John Vaughan?] to Col. Hampton, September 13, 1832; 7 1/2" x 11 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    L-3 Philadelphia, 2 pp. L. Unsigned. With regard to the possibility of the introduction of silk culture into the United States.
  - Letter to H.J.Anderson, Sept. 14, 1832; 7-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Mutilated. Forwards publications.
  - Freight receipts of packages shipped overseas by John Vaughan, Sept. 14-May 29, 1832-1841; American Philosophical Society
    Printed D.s filled in in ms. 15 items. Various sizes
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 15, 1832; 10x8; Harvard University
  - Robley Dunglison to John Vaughan, September 17, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    Librarian to the A.P.S., University of Virginia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has requested Carey and Lea to send a copy of his work on physiology to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Sept. 17, 1832; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Daniel Brent. 1p. and add., end. "Circular." Donates census returns.
  - H[enry] J[ames] Anderson to Jno. Vaughan, September 20, 1832; 8" x 9 3/4"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning A.P.S. Transactions, to be forwarded to Mr. Anderson for distribution.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Sept. 20, 1832; 10x8; Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864
    A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. (see Ms. Comm. to the APS. Medicine, Anatomy and physiology, no. 55.) Concerning colchicum.
  - Report of committee on [John G.E.] Heckewelder's paper on Indian names, Sept. 21, 1832; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Peter S.DuPonceau,Severin Lorich, and Charles Pickering. 2p.and end.: A.D. Bache. Cf. Minutes, p.627. Printed: APS Trans.,n.s.IV, 351 ff.
  - Report of committee on donation of fossils by Judge Bry, Sept. 21, 1832; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Rich[ar]d Harlan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.627.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1832; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volume.of the Royal Irish academy.
  - Rembrandt Peale to John Vaughan, October 1, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has send portrait of [William H. Furness?] to the care of Franklin Peale at the museum.
  - List of books presented to the A.P.S. by George Ord, 1832 October 5; American Philosophical Society.
    List of books presented to the A.P.S. Library by George Ord.
  - Letter to the secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 6, 1832; 10x8; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    L.S.: Joseph Maire Dantas. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, October 9, 1832; 6 3/4" x 8 1/2"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Book news. Has sent collection of French books to Society of Foreign Literature.
  - List of titles by J.G.V.de Moléon D., Oct. 10, 1832; 12x8; Moléon, J.-G.-V. de (Jean-Gabriel-Victor), 1784-1835
    3p. In French. Enclosed originally with letter from Moléon to the President of the APS; Oct. 10, 1832.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Oct. 10, 1832; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Moléon, J.-G.-V. de (Jean-Gabriel-Victor), 1784-1835
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Enc. In French. Donation. Requests membership. For enclosure, see Moléon. List of titles [Oct. 10, 1832].
  - Letter to the president [of the APS], Oct. 16, 1832; 8" x 11 1/2"; Labouderie, abbé (Jean de), 1776-1849
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Is president of the Société des antiquaires de France; desires to become a corresponding member of the APS.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Oct. 16, 1832; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Société des antiquaires de France
    Paris, L.S.: Laboudiere. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 17, 1832; 10X8; Templeman, George, d. 1852
    Washington, A.L.S. 4p. Reply to former letter concerning a set of congressional documents.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 17, 1832; 10x8; Templeman, George, d. 1852
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, London, Oct. 22, 1832; 9-1/2x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.H. Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Report of committee on [Richard] Harlan's papers on fossils, Nov. 2, 1832; 8x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: S.G. Morton, W.E. Horner and William Hembel. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.628. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., IV, 397 ff.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 3, 1832; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edwd. T. Bennett. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 3, 1832; 9x7-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    London, L.S.: Edw[ar]d T. Bennett. 2p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Nov. 7, 1832; 12x8; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Turner. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, November 7, 1832; 6 3/4" x 8 1/2"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has distributed A.P.S. Transactions, IV, no. 2.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1832; 10x7-1/2; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Dulong. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 16, 1832; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
  - S[ylvanus] Thayer to John Vaughan, November 19, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 3/16"; Thayer, Sylvanus, 1785-1872
    Millitary Academy, West Point, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses a check for $20, in payment for Transactions. FILM 403 FRAME 13-2
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Nov. 20, 1832; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jomard. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 26, 1832; 12-1/2x8; Netherlands. Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    The Hague, L.S.: Vanalan. 2p.and end. In Dutch. ----English translation. 1p. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1832 December 1; Parker, John
    Parker reports that he has forwarded publication to the Haarlem Society of Science.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, London, Dec. 5, 1832; 9x7; Bath and West and Southern Counties Society
    A.L.S.: B.Leigh Lye. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication of the APS.
  - Report of committee on A.D.Bache's paper on magnetism, Dec. 7, 1832; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: William Hembel and B.H.Coates. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.629. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 209 ff.
  - Report of committee on [Thomas] Say's paper on insects, Dec. 7, 1832; 4-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: C.Pickering and Richd. Harlan. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.629. Printed: Trans., n.s., vol. IV, 403 ff.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, December 12, 1832; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Children, J. G. (John George), 1777-1852
    British museum, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Is commanded by the Duke of Sussex, president of the Royal Society, to acknowledge his election to membership in the A.P.S. Promotion of friendly intercourse between the two societies.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 12, 1832; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 15, 1832; 9-1/2x8; Keating, William Hypolitus, 1799-1840
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards material.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, Finchurch Street, Dec. 20, 1832; 10x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Ar. Aikin. 1p. and add., end. APS will have books sent to it.
  - Report of committee on Hopkinson's paper on a python, Dec. 21, 1832; 8x9; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.629. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 121 ff.
  - Letter to P. S. Duponceau, as president of the Philosophical society, Dec. 25, 1832; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. The Hungarian academy of sciences, organized in the city of pest in 1829,[7] desirous of corresponding with similar institutions of learning, recommends itself to the Philosophical society of Philadelphia. Lists the officers.
  - Resolution to exchange publications with the Hungarian academy of science, Dec. 26, 1832; 6x1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1832; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
  - Memorandum of accounts of the American philosophical society to 1832, 7-1/2x12; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p.and end.
  - Prevailing winds and state of thermometer observed at Fort Union... From 1 Jany to 31 Aug 1834., 1 Jany to 31 Aug., 1833 to 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Hamilton, C. J. A.
    t.p., endorsement. 20 pp. Com. Presented to A.P.S.: November 4, 1836. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 693.
  - Receipts to the American philosophical society for water rent, Jan. 1, 1833-1847; Philadelphia
    D. 15 items. Various sizes.
  - Bills of exchange purchased by the APS, 1833 January 3- 1847 November 26; American Philosophical Society.
    Bils of exchange of various sizes. 15 items.
  - Report of committee on fund for raising a statue to Cuvier, Jan. 4, 1833; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: N.Chapman and Roberts Vaux. 1p. and end. Contains list of 23 names of contributors.
  - J. Adams to J[ohn] Vaughan, January 4, 1833; 8" x 9 13/16"; Adams, J.
    Charleston, S. C., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning an exchange of books with the library of the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 4, 1833; 9x7; London Institution
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W[illia]m Maltby. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - W[illia]m Shaler to John Vaughan, January 4, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Shaler, William, 1778?-1833
    Librarian to the A.P.S., Havana, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Donates to the A.P.S.: Revista...Cubana, 6, 7.
  - Letter to F. Arago, secretary of the Royal academy of sciences, Paris, Jan. 5, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, L.S. 2p. In French. Encloses bill of exchange for 1000 francs transmitted as the Society's part in the monument to be erected in honor of Baron Cuvier.
  - Letter to Charles Nagy, Jan. 5, 1833; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, Photo. of A.L.S. 3p. (from original in Magyar Tudomanyos Akadémia Konyutára, Budapeat.) APS will be happy to exchange with the Hungarian Academy of Sciences.
  - Letter to Charles Nagy, 1833 January 5; American Philosophical Society.
    Philadelphia, copy of A.L.S. 3p. (from original in Magyar Tudomanyos Akadémia Konyutára, Budapeat.) APS will be happy to exchange with the Hungarian Academy of Sciences.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 5, 1833; 8" x 12 3/4"; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Recommends Mr. Ploessel of Vienna as a maker of astronomical instruments.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 5, 1833; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 15, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Ducatel, Julius Timoleon, 1796-1849
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add.,end. Pertains to Girardin manuscripts which had been entrusted to Dr. Mease for the library of the American philosophical society.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for payment for indexing the manuscript catalogue of the American philosophical society library, Jan. 15, 1833; 3-1/2x8; D'Eyting
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 15, 1833; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Férussac, André-Étienne-Just-Paschal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Donates publications.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, January 16, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Baily, Francis, 1774-1844
    [London] L. 1p. Copy, on same sheet with letter from wm. Vaughan to John Vaughan, Jan. 17, 1833. Inquires how he can procure additional copies of Hassler's work on weights and measures.
  - Receipts to the A.P.S. for insurance payments on Philosophical Hall, 1833 Janury 18 - 1840 January 2; American Philosophical Society.
    Insurance receipts.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, London, Jan. 28, 1833; 9-1/2x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.H.Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Sam[ue]l Breck to John Vaughan, January 31, 1833; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Breck, Samuel, 1771-1862
    Harrisburg, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of pamphlet by Mr. [F. R.] Hassler. Will lay aside or send on any "Worthy" documentary matter.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Jan., 1833; 12x8; France. Direction générale des ponts et chaussées et des mines
    Paris, L.S.: Eurenny(?). 1p. and end. In French. Donates publications.
  - Edwin James to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, February 3, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 9/16"; James, Edwin, 1797-1861
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Albany, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. Encloses $10 dues.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Feb. 4, 1833; 8x5; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, L.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 5, 1833; 10x8; Keating, William Hypolitus, 1799-1840
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Thanks for publication.
  - F[rancis] Nichols to the secretaries of the A.P.S., February 6, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Nichols, F. (Francis), fl. 1795-1820
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Approves resolution of the A.P.S. that the resident members should class themselves in committees.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 11, 1833; 8" x 10"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Lexington,Ky., A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Acknowledges certain issues of the Transactions. Introduces the bearer, Mr. Dewees.
  - M[oncure] Robinson to Alex[ande]r D[allas] Bache, February 12, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Robinson, Moncure, 1802-1891
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 15, 1833; 10x8; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.: Quetelet. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, 1833 February 27; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Sparks thanks Dr. Franklin Bache for his letter of [February?] 15, mentioning the place where Mrs. Franklin died.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb., 1833; 9-1/2x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: J.F.Encke. 1p.and end. In German. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the APS, Feb., 1833; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: J. F.Encke. 1p. and end. In Latin. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March 1, 1833; 9x7-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Van der Vinne. 1p. and end. In Dutch. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., March 13, 1833; 10x8; Société géologique de France
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: J.Desnoyers. 3p.and add.,end. In French. Sends rules of the society. Wishes to exchange publications.
  - Letter to Chas. Nagy, March 26, 1833; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Letterpress copy of A.L.S. 2p.and end. Copy too blurred to read.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, March 29, 1833; 9x7-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    London, L.S.: Edw[ar]d T. Bennett. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - Report of committee on F. Nichols' paper on the solar system, April 5, 1833; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Franklin Bache and A.D.Bache. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.632.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, 1833 April 13; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Sparks returns the manuscript volume of Franklin's letters which will be published in May [1833].
  - Report of committee on Isaac Lea's paper on shells, April 19, 1833; 8x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin and A.D.Bache. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.632.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], April 19, 1833; 10x8; Kirckhoff, Chevalier de J. R. L.
    Anvers, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards volume.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, April 20, 1833; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. M. de Ferussac offers to furnish back numbers of the Bulletin of Sciences for thirty-one francs. Americans in Paris recommend Warden for consul.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., April 27, 1833; 10x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, L.S.: Van der Vinne. 1p. and end. In Dutch. Forwards publication.
  - J[acob] Randolph to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, Secretary of the A.P.S., April 27, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; Randolph, J. (Jacob), 1796-1848
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 30, 1833; 8x5; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards volumes.of the early Transactions of the APS.
  - Report of the committee appointed to have the projects of laws printed, May 3, 1833; 6 1/4" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin, Isaac Lea.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 4, 1833; 10x8; Mather, W. W. (William Williams), 1804-1859
    West Point, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Forwards material.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 4, 1833; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.of the Royal society and the Royal astronomical society.
  - Sam[uel] B. Meyler to Jno., May 14, 1833; 3 1/4" x 7 1/2"; Meyler, Samuel B.
    Vaughan, Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Wishes to borrow Woodhouse's Analytical Calculation.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 23, 1833; 10x8; Nagy, Károly, -1849
    Vienna, ALS 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes and telescope. (Prev. cataloged as May 23, 1838.)
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 23, 1833; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841. Nagy, Károly
  - Letter to the Academy of sciences of Philadelphia [A.P.S. ?], May 25, 1833; 8" x 10"; Akademiia nauk, St. Petersburg
    St. Petersburg, D.S: P.H. Fuss, perpetual secretary. 1p. and printed enc. -4p. Encloses a program of prizes offered for 1834 and 1835.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, May 28, 1833; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Accademia economico-agraria dei georgofili (Florence, Italy)
    L.S.: Leopoldo Pelli-Fabbroni. 3p. and add. In Italian. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1833 June 3, 5; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Regarding a case of books forwarded in February. The letter also relates that Americans in Paris recommend Warden for consul.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 13, 1833; 10x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Henry S. Farmer. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, June 13, 1833; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edw[ar]d T. Bennett. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 14, 1833; 10x8; American Colonization Society
    Washington, A.L.S.: P.R.Fendall. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for document. Will forward publication.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, June 14, 1833; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. A case of books, addressed to F. Fraley, for the Philosophical Society. was sent by packet in February.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 17, 1833; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, L.S.: Donald Gregory. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Bond of Mary Oldmixen and Maria Oldmixen, 1833 June 18; American Philosophical Society.
    Bond between Mary and Maria Oldmixen and the American Philosophical Society for the amount of two thousand dollars.
  - Report of the committee on printing the laws, July 19, 1833; 7" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Isaac Lea, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache.
  - Francis Dwight to John Vaughan, June 21, 1833; 4 15/16" x 7 3/4"; Dwight, Francis, 1808-1845
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Boston], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents specimens of native ore from Virginia to the A.P.S.
  - Report of the committee on publications in re the printing of an index for the four volumes of the Society's Transactions, June 21, 1833; 8" x 9 1/2"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.D.S.: Franklin Bache. Holds the printing of an index "necessary".
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 25, 1833; 8x5; Dannery, S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 5, 1833; 7 1/4" x 9"; Royal Society of London
    D.S.: Chas. Konig, For. Sec. R.S. 2p. and end. Announcement of medal to be awarded annually for the most important discoveries in physical and mathematical knowledge. Those for 1833 were awarded to Sir John F. W. Herschel and Prof. de Candolle.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 6, 1833; 10x8; James, Edwin, 1797-1861
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. Has completed his Chippewa testament. Would like to publish a Chippewa grammar under APS auspices.
  - Report of the committee on printing the laws and regulations, August 16, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Isaac Lea, Philip H. Nicklin. Report that the laws have been printed in a pamphlet of 46 pages.
  - Receipts to John Vaughan for the American philosophical society, Aug. 16, Aug. 26, 1833-1841; Philadelphia. Collector of Excise
    D. 9 items. Various sizes.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, August 18, 1833; 6 13/16" x 8 13/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Book news and comments.
  - Ch[ar]l[e]s Nagy to John Vaughan, August 20, 1833; 8" x 10"; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    Pest, 3 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Concerning a new method of constructing telescopes. Four hundred exiled Polish soldiers to be sent to the United States.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1833; 10-1/2x8; Institut de France
    Paris, A.L.S.: Cardot. 1p.and end.: "Letter from Pres. DuPonceau to M. Arago...[read Nov. 1, 1833]." In French. Thanks for money for monument to Cuvier. Printed: Hazard Register...; vol.14,190.
  - Letter to [P.S.] Duponceau, President of the A.P.S., Aug. 26, 1833; 8" x 10"; Académie royale des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: F. Arago. 2p. In French. Relative to the monument to be erected in memory of Cuvier. Printed: Hazard Register...; vol.14, 190.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Sept. 1, 1833; 9x7-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Van der Vinne In Dutch. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.